<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>

<c74object name='tc.preset' category='jsui, preset, pattrstorage'>

	<digest>
		A jsui replacement for the preset object.
	</digest>
	<description>
		tc.preset is a jsui clone of the preset object, but loaded with more features, such as preset organization through drag and drop, display as a scrollable list, auto-rewrite the saved JSON/XML file after any change.
		Contrary to the preset object, tc.preset has to be used in conjonction with a pattrstorage object.<modification class=""></modification>
	</description>


	<!--METADATA-->

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name='author'>Théophile Clet</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>preset</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>pattrstorage</metadata>
        <metadata name='tag'>jsui</metadata>
	</metadatalist>


	<!--ARGUMENTS-->

	<!-- <objarglist>

		<objarg name='pattrstorage' optional='0' type='symbol'>
			<digest>Name of the pattrstorage to control</digest>
			<description>Name of the pattrstorage this object should be linked to.</description>
		</objarg>

	</objarglist> -->


	<!--MESSAGES-->

	<methodlist>
		<method name="int">
			<digest>Recall numbered preset</digest>
			<description>Sending any integer will trigger the preset of the same number</description>
		</method>
		<method name="float">
			<digest>Interpolate between presets</digest>
			<description>Recalls the data from the preset specified by float. If the number falls between two whole numbers (e.g. 1.5), the pattrstorage object will interpolate between the data stored in the preset corresponding to the integer portion of the float and the data stored at the preset numbered one higher (e.g. 1.5 will cause pattrstorage to interpolate 50% between presets 1 and 2). See the interp message for more information about interpolation modes.</description>
		</method>
		<method name="bang">
			<digest>Recall last recalled preset</digest>
			<description>When a bang is received, the last triggered preset is triggered again.</description>
		</method>
        <!-- <method name="list">
			<digest>Function depends on inlet</digest>
			<description>Function depends on inlet</description>
		</method> -->
		<method name="pattrstorage">
			<digest>Link to named pattrstorage object</digest>
			<description>The word 'pattrstorage' followed by the name of an existing pattrstorage links the jsui to that pattrstorage.
				Make sure that pattrstorage outlet is connected to the jsui left inlet prior to send the message.
				If the word `pattrstorage`is sent alone, the jsui is unlinked from any pattrstorage.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="resync">
			<digest>Resync the jsui to the pattrstorage</digest>
			<description>The word 'resync' will repopulate the jsui with the current preset list from the pattrstorage. It is usefull in case you add/remove/edit presets without using the jsui.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="setlock">
			<digest>Lock or unlock selected preset</digest>
			<description>The word 'setlock' followed by a 0 or a 1 respectively unlocks or locks the currently selected preset in the jsui.
				Note that if select_mode is set to 1, the selected preset is not necessarily the last recalled one.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="setslotname">
			<digest>Set the name of the selected preset</digest>
			<description>The word 'setslotname' followed by a symbol sets that symbol as the name of the currently selected preset in the jsui.
				Note that if select_mode is set to 1, the selected preset is not necessarily the last recalled one.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="text">
			<digest>Set the name of the selected preset</digest>
			<description>Same as setslotname. Allows to connect the leftmost outlet of a textedit to the jsui and use it as an interface to rename the selected presets.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>


	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name='active_slot_color' get='1' set='1'  type='list' size='4' >
			<digest>Active slot color</digest>
			<description>Color of the last recalled preset</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name='autowriteagain' get='1' set='1'  type='int' size='1' >
			<digest>Automatic writeagain</digest>
			<description>When set to 1, the jsui will automatically send a "writeagain" message to its linked pattrstorage anytime a preset have been stored, moved, renamed, (un)locked or deleted, saving any change into the preset file immediately.</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name='bubblesize' get='1' set='1'  type='float' size='1' >
			<digest>Slot size</digest>
			<description>Size of the preset slots</description>
		</attribute>

	</attributelist>


	<!--RELATED-->

	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name='pattrstorage' />
		<seealso name='preset' />
		<seealso name='jsui' />
	</seealsolist>


</c74object>
